bpp.com 2011-11-25

# Privacy Policy

Last updated on: 19 September 2011

**Who are we and what is the purpose of this privacy policy?**

This privacy policy explains how BPP Holdings Limited and its subsidiary companies in the UK (together “BPP”; “we” or “us”) uses and protects any personal information which is collected from you when you use the following websites including any subdomains (collectively referred to in this privacy policy as the “Website”):

  * bpp.com
  * bppfinancialservices.com
  * bppprofessionaldevelopment.com
  * bppuc.com
  * bppbusiness.com
  * bpplawschool.com
  * bppstatus.com
  * bpp-international.com
  * acted.co.uk
  * bpptraining.com
  * classofthefuture.co.uk
  * bppathena.com
  * bppcollegepayments.com
  * bppcollegelis.wordpress.com
  * bppcollegevle.edublogs.org
  * bpphelp.wordpress.com
  * eql.co.uk
  * mpw.co.uk
  * lawprobono.com
  * bpptopcima.com
  * bppstudents.com

Personal information is information which can identify you as a living individual, whether by itself or when used in conjunction with other information which we hold or are likely to hold.

BPP Holdings Limited and each of its subsidiary companies are registered at Companies House. The subsidiary companies to which your personal information collected through the Website may be directed (as relevant) are BPP University College of Professional Studies Limited (which includes BPP Law School and BPP Business School), BPP Professional Education Limited (including BPP International School of Finance) both of which deliver training and courses, Mander Portman Woodward Limited, BPP Actuarial Education Limited, Actuarial Education Company Limited and BPP Learning Media Ltd which produces learning materials. For details of its and their registration numbers and registered office addresses please go to the "Company Details" section below. If you wish to contact us please go to the "Contact Us" section below.

This privacy policy is a part of and is incorporated into our Website Terms of Use.

**What if you do not accept the terms of this privacy policy?**

The Data Protection Act 1998 defines your rights as an individual in relation to your personal information and how it is used. Its purpose is to ensure that organisations like ours manage your personal information in a fair and sensible way.

If you do not agree to your personal information being used in accordance with this privacy policy please do not submit your personal information to us through the Website. Please note that your access to the products/services/materials offered on the Website may be restricted if you do not submit personal information when we ask you to do so. For example, if you are one of our staff members or students and if you wish to use certain pages of the Website you will need to register for this and then enter your name and password on the login page to gain access to the relevant pages. Otherwise you will not be able to access those pages.

**Updates and changes to this privacy policy**

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. Please check it accordingly. If you continue to use the Website after changes to this privacy policy have been made we will take this to mean that you have read and accepted those changes. You should not use the Website if you do not accept changes which are made to it. In addition, you should tell us if changes mean that you do not accept the way in which we use your personal information.

  * What personal information do we collect?
  * What is Sensitive Personal Data?
  * What do we do with your personal information?
  * What happens from a technical point of view when my personal information is submitted through the Website?
  * Who do we share your personal information with?
  * Will my personal information be transferred outside the UK and/or Europe?
  * Whistleblowing and compliance with US SOX Law
  * How to obtain copies of your personal information from us
  * How to help us ensure your personal information is accurate
  * Security
  * Usage statistics, cookies and web beacons
  * Linking
  * Direct marketing
  * Retention of your personal information 
  * Contact Us
  * Company Details

**What personal information do we collect?**

Depending on how you use the Website we will ask you to provide us with certain personal information.  For example, if you are one of our staff members or students (as referred to above) we will grant you access to certain pages only if you register to use them. Also, if you order products and/or services from the Website we will ask you to provide certain personal information to us. The information we ask for may include:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Date of birth
  * Email address
  * Phone number(s)
  * Fax number
  * Where you heard about us
  * Information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experiences with our products and services and contact preferences (please refer to the section “Direct Marketing” below for more information).  Some of this information may constitute Sensitive Personal Data (e.g. if your personal interests relate to your religious or other beliefs or your racial or ethnic origin) which is defined below. 
  * Credit/debit card information and/or delivery address information (if you order products on the Website)
  * Information you provide in any “free text” boxes on the Website (i.e. blank spaces where you are free to insert comments)

This list is not exhaustive and it may change or be updated in accordance with the nature of our services and as legal, regulatory and other good governance requirements require.

Wherever reasonably practicable we will distinguish between personal information which you must provide in order to be granted the access referred to in this section and information which you provide at your discretion.

Back to list

**What is Sensitive Personal Data?**

This is a more sensitive category of personal information which relates to, for example, a person’s race, sexual life, criminal allegations or offences, trade union membership or their mental or physical health.

Sensitive Personal Data may be relevant if you choose to attend our events (or other teaching sessions or events organised by us or on our behalf) and if you choose to submit information to us about, for example, your special needs or dietary requirements beforehand. The information you provide to us may include Sensitive Personal Data.

We make sure that Sensitive Personal Data is subject to additional controls. We would use it only in order to deliver our services to you, to meet your requirements or to deal with any requests made by you. We would only disclose it to any of the third parties referred to in the section “Who do we share your personal information with?” in the event that they need to know it (for example, if a third party service provider is organising a conference for us or is providing catering services at a conference) and subject to appropriate confidentiality obligations (as may be appropriate).

Back to list

**What do we do with your personal information?**

The legitimate purposes for which we use your personal information will depend upon how you use the Website.  They may include the following:

  * Internal record keeping and audits
  * Administration of the Website and our relationship with you including to provide products to you which you may order from us and/or to provide our services to you and to monitor those services
  * Dealing with and responding to any communication, enquiry or application which you submit to us and to provide you with appropriate services which may include sending your further information
  * Contacting you for research purposes including market research and to help us plan and improve our products and services.  We may contact you ourselves or ask outside research agencies to do so on our behalf (please refer to the section “Who do we share this information with” below). 
  * Conducting optional online surveys (e.g. to gauge our service, collect demographic information and other information that we may find useful)
  * Analysing patterns and trends of use and the uptake of our educational courses and facilities
  * (If you are a student or delegate on one of our courses) to administer tests and examinations in which you participate, to verify your results and to have the course and/or your papers and/or award internally or externally assessed and verified
  * Sending you direct marketing about products and services (but only when we have the appropriate consent(s) from you - please refer to the section “Direct Marketing” below)
  * Enabling BPP and its group companies, including the ultimate US parent company of all BPP companies, namely Apollo Group, Inc. and/or Apollo Global, Inc. of which it is a part (all of which are the Apollo Group Companies, as defined in the “Who do we share your personal information with” section below), to:

  *  provide information and marketing services related to our products and services,
  * carry out statistical analyses regarding the products and services offered by us or the Apollo Group Companies including analysing the profiles of customers, clients, students and staff together with the patterns and trends of use and the uptake of educational courses and facilities by and across BPP and its group companies including Apollo Group Companies based in the US; and 
  * improve efficiency, results, communications, marketing, processes, standards and procedures as a result of such information and marketing services and statistical analyses referred to above across BPP and its group companies and including Apollo Group Companies based in the US and/or for making use of additional expertise, experience, resource and facilities available from Apollo Group Companies based in the US.   

  * Fulfilling legal obligations to funding bodies
  * Ensuring compliance with legal, regulatory and other good governance obligations (please see “Whistleblowing and Compliance with US SOX Law” section below).

This list is not exhaustive and it may change or be updated in accordance with the nature of our work and as legal, regulatory and other good governance requirements require.  
You personal information may be kept in paper files and/or held in electronic form (e.g. on our IT systems, in emails or in data bases).

Back to list

**What happens from a technical point of view when my personal information is submitted through the Website?**

When your personal information is collected through a page on the Website it is directed into one or more IT systems. It is then stored and used depending on which BPP company or training entity the information needs to go to in order for (e.g.) your request for information to be processed, for you to be registered on a training course or for your to receive related course materials. Your personal information may be held on the IT system of the BPP group company (e.g. for the purpose of providing training or educational services to you) and/or on the system of another company (within or outside the BPP group of companies) outside the UK which is providing IT hosting or similar services, in accordance with a suitable contract in place with that company.

Back to list

**Who do we share your personal information with?**

The BPP company to whom your personal information is directed through the Website may transfer your personal information to other companies in the Apollo group of companies which includes:

  * Other companies in the BPP group of companies (including BPP Holdings Limited and its subsidiaries and affiliates); and
  * Apollo Group, Inc. and/or Apollo Global, Inc. (and subsidiaries and affiliates of each of them) which are companies based in the US

(together “Apollo Group Companies”).

We may make your personal information available to other businesses which we engage to help us run our business, for example to provide services to us.  This may include (this is not a definitive list) market research companies, providers of direct marketing services, training providers, suppliers of services relating to whistleblowing (please see the “Whistleblowing and Compliance with US SOX Law” section below) and IT hosting and maintenance providers.  In addition (if you are a student or delegate on one of our courses) we may make your personal information available to external awarding bodies and auditors which verify your test and examination results, in order to obtain accreditations for you.  We may also make it available to relevant central government departments or other external bodies which oversee the quality of the services we provide and the process of awarding qualifications and accreditations.  In accordance with the requirement of the Data Protection Act 1998 we would impose restrictions and standards in our written contract with them in order to ensure they keep your personal information secure and that they use it only for the purpose for which we provide it to them.  If these businesses are outside the UK, the section “Will my personal information be transferred outside the UK?” below will be relevant.

We may be required by law or for tax or other purposes to disclose your personal information to local or central government authorities or official agencies.  We may be required by law or legal process (i.e. by a court or tribunal) to release it to other external organisations.  We may also release it to parties to which you authorise us to release it.  In addition, there may be circumstances in which it is necessary for us to disclose your personal information to external companies or organisations in order to protect our customers or our own interests but this would be carried out in compliance with applicable privacy laws.

We will not sell your personal information to any third party except where necessary as part of our legitimate business processes (e.g. in the event that our management or administration is to be taken over by an external organisation).  Should we do this we would ensure it was carried out in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

Back to list

**Will my personal information be transferred outside the UK and/or Europe?**

We may wish to transfer your personal information to the US or to other countries (for example, to an overseas service provider, training product manufacturer, agent or supplier) for the purposes described above.  If you are using the Website from outside the UK other laws may apply to your personal information.  We are not subject to local laws applicable in your country and this privacy policy may not be compliant with those local laws.  You should not submit your personal information to us unless you accept this position.

We may transfer your personal information to the US to Apollo Group, Inc. and/or Apollo Global, Inc. for the purposes described above (including but not limited to the statistical analysis purpose described above).  
The Website may be hosted on servers located outside the UK and/or Europe and maintenance and support services for the Website may be provided from outside the UK and/or Europe.  This means your personal information may be stored in other countries.

All of this means that your personal information may be transferred to other countries which do not have the same privacy laws as are applicable in the UK and other parts of Europe.  However, in order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, damage or loss of your personal information, we take suitable physical and electronic, organisational and technical measures to this end, in accordance with our obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998. In addition, any transfer of your personal information to another country would be carried out in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

Back to list

**Whistleblowing and compliance with US SOX Law**

We have explained above that your personal information may be used for the purpose of ensuring compliance with legal, regulatory and other good governance obligations and that it may be disclosed to service providers.  This includes use for the purpose of enabling Apollo Group Companies to comply with The US Sarbanes–Oxley Act of 2002 (“SOX Law”).  The purpose of the SOX Law is to guard against unethical, improper or illegal business conduct including, for example, accounting and financial fraud, conflicts of interest and white collar crime.

The Apollo companies may appoint one or more service providers to assist them in managing a whistleblowing helpline and a webpage which act as a reporting mechanism (the “Helpline”) to ensure compliance with the SOX Law, local laws and regulations relating to similar purposes and any other laws and regulations which relate to fraudulent, illegal or unethical behaviour.  It is possible that a BPP employee, student or faculty teacher may report matters of concern through the Helpline and that your personal data may be used by the Apollo companies, its service provider(s) which manage the Helpline and by BPP for the purpose of investigating any such report and taking remedial action thereafter.  For example, if a BPP employee suspects that an earlier employee is misusing company records for his own purposes or is committing a fraud which involves your personal information, he may report this through the Helpline.  Should this happen, your personal information would only be used for the purpose of ensuring compliance by the Apollo companies and the BPP companies with the relevant laws and regulations.  Wherever reasonably possible your personal information would be anonymised prior to use for the purpose of investigations and remedial action so that it does not relate to you, but in some specific circumstances this may not be possible as it may prohibit a full investigation.

Any transfers to the Apollo companies and its service provider(s) which manage the Helpline and which may also be in the US would be carried out in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (please see the section directly above).  There would be contractual measures in place with those service providers to protect your personal information (please see the “Who do we share your personal information with?” section above) to ensure that (first) it is used only in accordance with Apollo’s instructions (in particular, the instructions of the relevant BPP company) and for the purpose of investigating suspected compliance issues, and (secondly) that it keeps such personal information secure.  In addition, reasonable efforts are used to ensure that the website related to the Helpline and messages sent through that portal are secure and in particular, they are encrypted.  A limited number of specially trained Apollo and BPP employees only will have access to your personal information which is disclosed through the Helpline where and to the extent that this is necessary for the purposes of carrying out their roles.  In any event, their access will be very limited, secure, carefully controlled and justified.  To this end they will be subject to appropriate confidentiality obligations. 

We encourage our employees to use the Helpline in good faith and only for serious or substantial issues which cannot properly be reported via other means. 

Provided reports are made through the Helpline in good faith, we try to protect your identity as much as possible.  However, we cannot guarantee this (especially in subsequent court or tribunal proceedings) and we are required to inform the subject of the reports about the allegation(s).  Those subjects have the right to request their own personal information, as do you (see directly below).

Back to list

**How to obtain copies of your** **personal information from us**

You can ask to access the personal information which the relevant BPP company (i.e. the company to which your personal information is directed through the Website) may hold about you or you can ask to be provided with a copy of it.  In some circumstances the relevant BPP company may provide access not copies.  It may charge a nominal fee in order to cover some of its administration costs in responding to your request and it is permitted to do this under the Data Protection Act 1998.  You would need to put your request in writing.  You may email or write to the relevant BPP company for this purpose by using the addresses in the “Contact Us” section below.

Back to list

**How to help us ensure your personal information is accurate**

If you think that any personal information we have about you is inaccurate please email or write to us using the details in the “Contact Us” section below. We will amend your personal information if we believe it contains factual errors or is out of date.

Back to list

**Security  **

We are committed to ensuring that we keep your personal information secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, damage or loss of your personal information, we take suitable physical and electronic, organisational and technical measures to this end, in accordance with our obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998. The internet is not a secure means of communication. Emails may be intercepted by other people or organisations.  We cannot guarantee the security of personal information sent to us through these websites (although as explained below, we have taken steps to protect your credit/debit card details).  Any communication sent to us through this website or by email is sent at your own risk.

In the event that you place an order on these websites we offer the use of a secure server. We use industry-standard secure server software (SSL) which encrypts information you send us as part of a transaction. This improves the security of the processing of your credit/debit card details.

When using the secure sections of our websites your browser should display a padlock icon which verifies that the site possesses SSL certification. You can verify the security of these pages by clicking on this padlock icon.

If passwords are used on these websites you are responsible for ensuring that you keep your own password confidential and do not permit other people to use it.  Please contact us promptly using the details in the “Contact Us” section below if you believe your password may have been compromised.

Back to list

**Usage statistics, cookies and web beacons**

Your browser typically reveals a certain amount of information to our web server when you visit our websites, including but not limited to the IP address of your internet service provider, the name and version of your operating system, the name and version of your browser, the date and time of your visit and which pages of our websites you visit. This information may be used to create statistics which help us to improve this website. The information obtained in this way does not identify you personally. However, we may review our server logs for security purposes, such as to detect intrusions into our network.  If we suspect criminal activity we might share our server logs - which contain visitors’ IP addresses - with the police or other appropriate investigative authority and they may use that information to trace and identify individuals.

We may also use “cookies” on our websites. Cookies are small text files which your browser places on your hard drive so that the website can recognise you on future visits to that site. They make it easier for you to maintain your preferences on our websites, and allow us to tailor the sites to your preferences, provide features such as shopping baskets and measure your use of our sites.

We may also use electronic images known as “web beacons” on this website and in communications generated from using and/or registering on this website, such as promotional emails.  Web-beacons usually work in conjunction with cookies.

We mainly use cookies to measure general visitor numbers to our websites, and also to monitor click-through rates from advertisements hosted on third-party websites. These statistics are gathered in aggregate and do not identify individual visitors, but allow us to monitor the effectiveness of our website and our marketing efforts. From time to time, we may also use cookies and / or web beacons to track the effectiveness of promotional emails that we may send to named individuals. In these cases, additional cookies enable us to monitor those individuals’ responses to these emails (e.g. if recipients click on links contained in the emails). We are therefore sometimes able to associate visits to our websites with identifiable individuals, allowing us to monitor response rates and thus the effectiveness of these communications channels. In all of the above examples, our cookies do not themselves contain any personally identifiable information, only encrypted session IDs that can only be interpreted by our websites’ tracking software.

You can, should you choose, configure your browser not to accept cookies from our and/or other websites, and also to delete all cookies currently stored on your computer. You can find out how to do this for your particular browser by clicking ‘help’ on your browser's menu or by visiting [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html). However, some of our website features such as user registration or shopping carts may not function if you disable cookies.

Back to list

**Linking**

We may link to other websites which are not within our control.  Such links are provided for your convenience.   In addition, other websites outside our control may link to the Website.  We are not responsible for the content of any external sites we provide links to or which link to the Website. Once you have left our website, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.   

Back to list

**Direct marketing**

The BPP company to which your personal information is directed through the Website may wish to contact you by post or telephone, by fax or by email, SMS, voicemail, or other electronic methods which become relevant in the future to tell you about its products or services, those of other members of the Apollo Group Companies, and/or those of carefully selected third parties.  This is known as “direct marketing”.  Whenever we collect your personal information on the Website we will make it clear if it may be used for direct marketing purposes.  At the same time we will seek your consent to receive this or we will permit you to opt-out of receiving this (depending on applicable laws). 

In direct marketing sent by any of the electronic methods described above the relevant BPP company would provide you with a simple way to refuse further direct marketing by the relevant method. 

If you refuse further electronic marketing, the relevant BPP company(ies) would not necessarily remove your personal information from its/their database(s) but as soon reasonably possible it/they would note that you had changed your mind.  This means that it/they may continue to hold your personal information (including your contact details), but in a repressed form, and only to ensure that it/they did not contact you further for the purpose of sending marketing by electronic means where you had objected to this.

If at any other time you wish to change your mind about your direct marketing preferences please contact us promptly using the details in the “Contact Us” section below. 

Back to list

**Retention of your personal information**

In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 we will ensure your personal information is not kept longer than necessary for the relevant purpose(s) by us or by any of the other parties referred to above. 

In particular, personal information collected through the Helpline for the purpose of compliance with the SOX Law and equivalent or related local laws and regulations, and all documents (electronic and hard copy) related to the same, or to any related investigation, will be kept for so long as is required by law or legal process or as strictly necessary to fulfil the legitimate purpose for which it was collected.  This will be for an appropriate time period following completion of verification or investigation (or on the completion of resultant proceedings).  Where information is known to be unreliable, irrelevant or excessive, it will be securely deleted as soon as possible. 

Back to list

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions, concerns or comments or if you would like further information about this privacy policy and how we handle your personal information please email us at [terms@bpp.com](mailto:terms@bpp.com), telephone us on 0845 075 1100 or write to our Customer Services Director at BPP Holdings Limited, Aldine House, Aldine Place, 142-144 Uxbridge Road, London, W12 8AW.

Back to list

**Company Details**

Name of company | Company registration number | Registered office address  
---|---|---  
BPP Holdings Limited | 01245304 | 

BPP House, Aldine Place,  
142-144 Uxbridge Road  
London  
W12 8AA  
  
BPP Professional Education Limited

| 04546335 | 

BPP House, Aldine Place,  
142-144 Uxbridge Road  
London  
W12 8AA  
  
BPP University College of Professional Studies Limited | 02609100 | 

BPP House, Aldine Place,  
142-144 Uxbridge Road  
London  
W12 8AA  
  
BPP Actuarial Education Limited | 02904358 | 

BPP House, Aldine Place,  
142-144 Uxbridge Road  
London  
W12 8AA  
  
Actuarial Education Company Limited | 03062375 | 

BPP House, Aldine Place,  
142-144 Uxbridge Road  
London  
W12 8AA  
  
BPP Learning Media Limited | 05959432 | 

BPP House, Aldine Place,  
142-144 Uxbridge Road  
London  
W12 8AA  
  
Mander Portman Woodward Limited | 01280778 | 

BPP House, Aldine Place,  
142-144 Uxbridge Road  
London  
W12 8AA  
  
Back to top
